<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activities on Dat Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://datng87.github.io/tags/activities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activities on Dat Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 11:14:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datng87.github.io/tags/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Map using Leaflet</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-leaflet-library-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 11:14:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-leaflet-library-experiment/</guid>
      <description>In this activity, I used the leaflet library to visualise the worldwide earthquakes in the last 7 days. The up-to-date data was pulled from United States Geological Survey, (USGS) through an API call. The USGS is responsible for providing scientific data about natural hazards, the health of our ecosystems and environment; and the impacts of climate and land-use change. Their scientists develop new methods and tools to supply timely, relevant, and useful information about the Earth and its processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive DIY visualization</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-interactive-visualization-d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-interactive-visualization-d3/</guid>
      <description>In this activity, I use the data from 2014 ACS 1-year estimates https://factfinder.census.gov/faces/nav/jsf/pages/searchresults.xhtml.
The purpose is to use D3 to demonstrate the ability to build a personal customised interactive chart using D3 to visualise the relationship between health risks and social demography backgrounds.
Interactive chart using D3 We can see there are some correlation between Poverty and lack of healthcare, or correlation between obesity and household Income&amp;hellip;
Visit https://datng87.github.io/customised-interactive-chart-with-D3/ for a live demo website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Dashboard using Plotly</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-plotly-library-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 11:14:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-plotly-library-experiment/</guid>
      <description>In this activity, I built an interactive dashboard to explore the Belly Button Biodiversity dataset, which catalogues the microbes that colonise human navels.
The dashboard shows the background of each individual and what type of bacteria was found in that person&amp;rsquo;s belly.
Interactive dashboard Visit https://datng87.github.io/Belly-Button-Biodiversity-viz-plotly/ for a live demo website. The code can be found at https://github.com/datng87/Belly-Button-Biodiversity-viz-plotly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping - Latest Mars News</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-web-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 11:14:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-web-scraping/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I&amp;rsquo;ll build a web application that scrapes the data from other websites regarding MARS and displays the information in an HTML page.
The tools used in this project are:
Flask BeautifulSoup Pandas Requests/Splinter. Mongo DB HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Jupiter Notebook for debugging purposes on how the scraped data looks like. How does it work: The application has a refresh button on top. Once the refresh button is clicked, the web application will run and scrape new data from other sites.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
