<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on Dat Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://datng87.github.io/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on Dat Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datng87.github.io/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning project: Prediction of Movie ratings</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>Background and Context: The Movie World: Defining the problem Movie industry is a volatile high investment / high risk industry.
After two decades of boom in terms of volume and revenue. The last five years has seen a decline in revenue and the last three years, a reduction in volume.
Understanding the drivers for success is critical to minimise financial and reputational risk.
Measures of Success Movie ratings come from a wide range of features and can be used as one proxy as a measure of success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ETL project: Coffee Worldwide consumption and production analysis</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>As a coffee lover, I am always keen to explore the data regarding coffee production, import/export and consumption worldwide.
In this project, I will visualise the above data on various charts, including choropleth, line chart and bar chart. The charts are interactive, and the user can choose multiple filters to display the desired data.
This is a completed standalone project in which the data was loaded to Postgres database and hosted online (Heroku).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Fatal vehicles crashes in USA for the last 10 years</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/project1/</guid>
      <description>Road traffic is the most common traffic in the world. We commute daily using cars, motorbikes, or buses &amp;hellip; How safe for us to go out of the house and enter road traffic? Does road traffic become safer in the last ten years? Which states have the most incidents? What are some of the high-risk factors involved in vehicle crashes? I used the dataset from https://crashviewer.nhtsa.dot.gov/CrashAPI/ to get the crash data in the USA for the last ten years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather visualization - where should I go</title>
      <link>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-weather-visualisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datng87.github.io/post/activity-weather-visualisation/</guid>
      <description>In this activity, I&amp;rsquo;ll take the weather data of 500+ randomly selected cities around the world then analyse the data to see any relations between cities lat/lon and its weather.
Here is how I approached the problem:
Firstly, I generated 500+ random lat/lon data Used citipy to find the nearest city to those lat/lon Then, I connect to the weather API (https://api.openweathermap.org/data/2.5/weather) to take the weather data of those cities The last step is to use Pandas to prepare the data and visualise it Below are some findings:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
